I am very honored to participate in this online academic seminar.
I will share with you how I transformed from a traditional fashion designer
to a 3D digital fashion designer.
Today's PPT will explain to you from a technical point of view
what kind of technical skills we need to support different application products.
When Mr. Ma was speaking just now,
I saw that some of the students were concerned about this issue.
When we make digital works, what software do we need to use?
Today, in this PPT, I will simply share with you.
I will also explain to you what kind of software we need to master
according to different projects and different skill levels.
Through this introduction, I will help you to establish a concept
of digital fashion.
That is to say, what kind of work effect do I want to achieve in the future?
In which direction should I work?
What kind of digital software do I need to learn?
Please help me to turn to the second page.
First of all, I will briefly introduce myself to you.
My name is Liu Wanping.
I graduated from Dalian University of Art and Design in 2005.
I am a fashion designer.
I graduated in 2005
and I have been involved in the design and development of fashion products
in the clothing industry since 2018.
In 2018, I started to get in touch with Cloud3D
and started my technical transformation.
Now, I am actually running my own 3D fashion design studio.
The main content of the studio is also for some enterprises,
including some universities and some companies,
to do modeling and modeling services for enterprises.
Then, the faculty will take part in some 3D courses.
At the same time, I will also give some training to enterprises inside the enterprise.
Personally, I will also share some of my daily skills and experiences
in using software on Xiaohongshu and Bilibili.
I also want to help those who want to enter this industry
and learn this software to grow quickly.
Since 2018,
I have transformed from a traditional designer
to a digital fashion designer.
In 2018,
I was in charge of the design and development of the entire product.
The problem I faced was that the cost of product design and development
at that time was very high and the efficiency was very low.
There was no way to quickly adopt this kind of fast-changing market.
So, I wanted to find a kind of fast-changing product
that can be used in many different ways.
So, I wanted to find a solution at that time.
In the process of finding a solution,
I came into contact with Cloud3D.
This is why I started a transformation of my entire design skills.
Let's look at the second page and the third page.
You can see that I have summarized this scroll
from 2018 to…
Please turn to the top page.
From 2018 to 2015,
for the entire seven years,
the bottom of the scroll is based on what I have participated in
and some of the projects I have participated in.
These projects all use our 3D fashion technology
to participate in them.
So, the content of the project
from solving traditional fashion design
to the future,
in the marketing section,
to the customer, the customer on the C-section,
to carry out virtual fashion display and pre-sale.
So, it covers the entire industry chain,
from the development to the mid-end sales.
In fact, all the sections are involved.
So, in the upper half of this scroll,
there are more projects that I have participated in
across the industry.
For example,
the 3D modeling that I collaborated with
the Beijing Contemporary Art Museum,
and then to show some conceptual costumes,
including to sell their own digital products
on Xiaohongshu,
as well as to show some of the IP designs
of my own in this Yuan Yizhou exhibition.
Okay, then please turn to the next page.
In this page,
I have listed out,
for those who are going to work in the fashion industry in the future,
whether you are a traditional designer,
or you are a fashion designer yourself,
we may be at the physical level,
communicating with each other online,
and then everyone on a platform,
on the company's platform,
to complete the design and development of our products.
This is a simple process of our traditional era.
Then, with the development of digital,
including the network,
and its technology,
then now,
as a designer,
its work content has also changed a little.
When we have mastered these digital tools,
in fact,
we do not need to be limited to a certain platform,
or limited to a certain physical geographical location,
to carry out a collaboration.
At the same time,
the works that we can show,
it can also be more creative,
to break through this traditional physical material,
a limitation of this material.
Okay, let's look at the next page.
This page is what I actually want to express today.
So you can see in the vote,
I have divided the ability into three levels.
Let's look at the first level from the bottom.
If we say that in the future,
everyone is going to enter the fashion industry,
to do design,
or to do production,
or sales,
then in this level,
in fact, we can master Cloud 3D,
to be able to master all of these main functions of Cloud 3D,
to be able to realize this kind of virtual sample production through Cloud 3D,
and then to involve this virtual sample into our entire development process,
and then to improve the efficiency of our entire design and development process,
so that our,
how to say,
let our virtual sample,
to replace the white flag of our many times in the past.
At this stage,
that is to say,
as long as we master Cloud 3D,
this one software is enough to meet our daily work needs.
Then we look at the second ability level.
When our work scope is involved in our clothing sales,
we need to show this virtual service to our sales team,
to show it to our C-end customers,
to do pre-sales or to do customization.
So in this scenario,
then for this technical staff,
his ability to operate the software is going to be stronger.
So at this point,
we only know how to use Cloud 3D,
which may not be enough for our work.
At this point,
we need to learn how to use Blender,
or CCD,
Maya,
this kind of traditional 3D modeling software,
to assist Cloud to realize a combination of different scenarios,
as well as our animation production.
In addition,
in order to achieve this kind of high-end fabric material presentation,
well,
just now,
some students have also asked,
in fact,
in terms of the material presentation,
it is also,
well,
it is divided into two parts.
One part,
maybe we can use some scanning equipment
to use the material in the real world
to perform a surface texture sample,
including its physical material sample,
and then use the equipment to import it into our software to use.
Then there is another one,
that is,
we can use something like Substance 3D,
Substance Painter,
as well as this kind of digital,
this kind of drawing,
3D drawing software,
to make some digital materials.
Well,
if we want to present more perfect details,
then this kind of software
is what we need to learn and master.
Then we look at the third level.
If our application scenario is similar to digital art,
I want to do this advertising and marketing,
and then be able to make this kind of比較炫的場景,
including details,
animation,
such a comprehensive display of a work,
then at this time,
we will need more 3D software.
At the same time,
because now with this AI technology,
it is getting more and more mature,
AI is going to assist these 3D software to generate videos,
to generate models,
to generate character animations,
so that it can be more efficient
to complete our part of digital marketing.
Please turn to the next page.
So,
in the face of different levels,
our employment direction has actually also changed.
As before,
because I have been doing design and research in the traditional clothing industry,
then after I was transferred,
my actual work scope,
including the industry I am in contact with,
has also changed.
I am no longer limited only to the clothing industry.
So,
when you have mastered a variety of 3D modeling software,
and mastered some AI drawing technology,
you can do some cross-industrial cooperation.
For example,
you can collaborate with the advertising and marketing industry,
and collaborate with the industry of CG games.
Please turn to the next page.
Next,
I will give you some specific examples of what I have done.
Then,
based on these examples,
I will tell you what kind of work we can achieve
under different levels of capabilities,
what kind of work can be completed,
and what kind of effect can be achieved.
Please turn to the next page.
This part
is what I just described,
the ability level 1.
Its main application scene
is within the clothing industry,
at the design and development threshold.
We are going to reduce the cost of development,
and increase efficiency.
This is the content of the work.
What you see in this group
is actually a new series of projects
that I have proposed according to the client,
including the color of the fabric.
Then,
according to the fabric that he recommended,
I will give him the style.
This is the design of the whole series of designs.
In the past,
we may need to draw a picture first,
then do a white batch,
and then do a sample.
After doing the sample,
we can see what kind of effect this dress has.
After using the digitalization process,
we can say that
the whole process is a kind of paperless office.
That is to say,
after I got the client's creative plan from the beginning,
I can directly use Cloud 3D
at the computer end.
I can use Cloud 3D
to do a design simulation of the whole series of products.
After the simulation,
I can do a model synthesis through AI.
At this time,
you can basically see the effect of the clothing
after it is manufactured.
Then,
when this effect,
when the synthesis effect of AI appears,
you can do a style evaluation
for sales internally.
At the same time,
you can also put it on,
if we have our own website,
you can also put it on the website
for a client's pre-sale.
Then,
you can take a look at the client's reaction to these styles.
through this way,
we can save the time and time wasted
on the material of our production,
the whole design,
and the entire design development.
At the same time,
this kind of digital sample,
it doesn't mean that
after we finish making a digital version,
it will be useless.
It can actually be accumulated
as a basis for our design development
for the next season.
Then,
in this way,
in each season,
if we say that
for the classic style,
we can make a design development
for the next season,
for example,
for the classic style,
we only need to put new fabric
in the 3D software
to see its effect.
Then,
this also greatly reduces
an error in our communication.
Then,
in this process,
in fact,
the entire design department's
work process
will have some major changes.
In the past,
in the entire design process,
the work of the designer
is very important.
Then,
the communication between the designer
and the designer
is often a difficult point.
It is also a point
where everyone spends
more time and energy.
Then,
I personally think that
this kind of software,
such as Cloud 3D,
it applies to the process
of our development.
In fact,
it is to pull everyone
to communicate
in one context.
Then,
we all communicate
in this 3D interface.
Then,
this will make the efficiency
of each of us
more efficient.
Then,
let's take a look at
the next page.
In the next page,
this page
is called
the digital sample 1.
It plays a role
in the production
and manufacturing
of our production
section.
This series
is actually
the digital sample 1
that I made
for the customer
during the epidemic.
Because during the epidemic,
in the past,
we may be the factory
to the customer
to carry out
production and manufacturing.
We will
make a series
of
a style
of washing
all of it
into clothes
and send it to the customer
for confirmation.
Then,
during the epidemic,
we have to use
this kind of online
digital sample 1
to confirm it.
At this time,
we shorten
our sample 1
back and forth
express delivery
including
the time cost
and material cost
of our production.
Then,
in fact,
in the cloud software,
it will also provide
this kind of
industrialized platform.
Then,
we will put
all the industrial
version of this board
on this industrialized platform
to evaluate
our different models
and different models
corresponding to
this platform.
In fact,
this model
is very effective.
Please turn to the next slide.
So,
to summarize,
our entire
technical ability
and technical balance.
So,
in the first level,
in fact,
whether you are
a designer
or a board designer,
in this level,
um,
the board
is
faster
to use
this cloud software
because
it has
the advantage
of the board
itself.
So,
it can learn
to make
this kind of
virtual
sample clothes
very quickly.
So,
designers
at this level
may seem
a little bit
tired.
The point of being tired
is that we often
don't know
enough about
this craft
and model.
So,
if you have
a partner
who is
a design
professional,
then
when you
enter the business
and enter
this digitalized
digital sample
process,
you will
have the ability
to make
a certain
improvement
at this level.
So,
with these abilities,
you can
quickly
complete
this kind of
high-end
clothing
type of
production.
Let's turn to the next one.
Um,
here,
in fact,
it is a proportion
of the ability.
You can see that
in this proportion,
our Cloud3D
software
is relatively
large.
So,
it can
be used
for some
functional
and work
needs.
So,
in addition,
if we can
design
and
include
some
flat
software
PS
operations,
then
making
this kind
of high-end
clothing,
including
the next
part,
production
it will
be
our production
and sales.
So,
now,
what you see
in this series,
in fact,
it is this 3D
simulation
of the
clothes
and our
real
people
to do
this kind of
e-commerce
detailed
display.
So,
this kind of
workflow,
in fact,
it is because
this project
was done
relatively
recently.
We
did
this project
with
Xinyu Productions.
So,
in this
platform,
he also
put all
the clothes
of the
new
generation
for him
to make
this kind
of virtual
clothing.
Then,
the virtual
clothing
will be
combined
with the
photos
taken
by the
company.
The whole
clothing
is also
created
for e-commerce.
So,
the whole
clothing
is also
a classic
style of
the past brand.
But for this year,
we may need
to change
a material
and some
craftsmanship
for the
pre-sale.
So,
at this time,
we may not
need to
make
real clothes.
We can
directly change
the material
and put it
on the e-commerce
to carry out
a sales test
of the
consumer.
After the
test data is
available,
we will
assist the
company
to make
some predictions
of the
production
and
the production
quantity.
Please
help me
to
translate
it to the
next slide.
So,
in this
level,
we need to
face the
consumer.
At this time,
we need to
use
Blender,
including
PT,
and SA.
PT and SA
are all
this kind of
text-based
software.
So,
you can
go back
and search
online.
This kind of
software
will also
have some
corresponding
tutorials.
So,
at this stage,
the designer's
ability to
make
some creative
product
images.
Please
help me
to
translate
it to the
next slide.
So,
at this
level,
we can
see that
the
cloud
capacity
ratio
is not
that
big.
At this
time,
if you
can
master
PS,
AI,
and
software,
you will be
able to
make
a lot
of
digital
art
and advertising
marketing.
This part
is about
digital art
and advertising
marketing.
This part
requires
a comprehensive
3D software
production
capability.
Its main
application
scene is
around
2021,
2022.
Everyone
will be able
to
make
digital
products
for
sale.
This part
is also
some digital
products
I made
at that time,
including
some art
exhibitions.
For this part,
my application
software is
like
Cloud,
including
ZB,
ZBrush,
Blender,
PT,
and
some other
rendering
software.
I also
have
some
software
that
can
be used
for
digital
art.
I also
have
some software
like
Unity
to
make
digital
art
more
efficient.
This part
is about
digital
art
exhibitions
in
the
future.
If you
want to
learn
about
digital art
in the
future,
I also
recommend
you to
learn
about
digital art
in the
future.
I also
have
some
advertising
on
the
big
screen
as well.
I listed
some
basic
software
in the
description box.
If you
want to
learn
about
digital art,
you will
need
more
software
to
learn
about
digital art.
If you
want to
learn
about
digital art,
you
will need
more
software.
If you
want to
learn
about
art,
I will
share with
you
the
production
process
and the
software
I used
in this
work.
Let's
look at
the
process.
First,
I used
the
Me
Journey
to create
a series
of
concepts
based
on
the
concept
I
created.
Then,
I made
the
costumes
and
accessories
into
Blender.
Because
my character
needs
to be
different
from
the
default
model
in
Clo
,
I
made
the
hair
of
the
character
in
a
pattern.
After the
pattern is
made,
it will
be
added to
Blender
to
create
scenes
and lights
and
to
show
the
material.
This is
the
creative
process
of
art.
Let's
look at
case
2.
Case
2 is
a
3D
process.
In order to
make the
character
more
realistic,
we combined
AI to
create the
model's
face.
Let's
look at
the
process.
In addition
to
the
previous
process,
I
made
clothes
with
Clo
3D
to
create
scenes
in
UE5.
Because
UE5 is
very
realistic
in
creating
scenes
and
creating
scenes
in
UE5.
At the
same time,
I also
made
animation
in
UE5.
In the
end,
I
made
the
model's
face
to
make
the model
more realistic.
Now,
after 7.1,
Clo
has already
made
the model
to
create
AI faces.
When
it was
working,
it didn't
have this
function yet,
so it
had to
use
other
AI
production
tools
to
make
the model
look
more realistic.
So,
I
hope
this video
can help
you
understand
how to
create
scenes
in
UE5.
Thank you.